# FENET GIRMA

**Full stack Developer** 

+251 970 386 940

@ fenutigist@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Q Alem Gena

Full Stack Developer with over 10 years of experience in Java/JS, Angular, Vue, React, Python, NumPy, SciPy, Scikit-learn. Led development of \$500K research project which was deemed a "gold standard" by the client. Increased client's revenue 2-fold after fine-tuning AI/ML-based algorithms. Well-acquainted with HR methodologies.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### B.A. in Software Engineering

Addis Ababa Science and Technology University

GPA 3.6 / 4.0

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Full stack Developer

**Boyle** 

🗰 2018 - Present 👂 San Fransisco, CA

Boyle is an international Technology and Management Consulting Group with a rapid pace development and innovative solutions for demanding projects. I work as a full-stack developer here, responsible for building, deploying and maintaining internal web applications.

- Hired, trained and leading an Agile team of 7 full-stack developers
- Developed indexed database architecture using SQL procedures and triggers for 10 different applications
- Worked with Core Java to develop automated solutions to include web interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Web services
- Worked with a committee of 6 members to organise fun-activities for the emplovees

## Full Stack Developer

Lauzon

iii 2013 - 2018 ♀ San Fransisco, CA

Lauzon is a universal digital loyalty program that offers unique and fun rewards at the places you love.

- Hired, trained and lead Agile team of 7 full-stack developers
- Simultaneously created & maintained scheduled jobs in SQL Server for space maintenance and daily backups of system and user databases for 10 clients
- Increased company revenue by 30% within 2 months after developing and implementing business logic for over 20 features
- Designed and Developed UI design for over 15 clients using CSS, HTML, ASP.NET, Vue, and React; websites scoring over 85 on Lighthouse

## **Solution Architect**

**Keeling Group** 

**=** 2010 - 2013 Palo Alto, CA

Keeling Group is a leading Digital Product Studio in California, helping companies to thrive on mobile apps, the web, VR/AR and IoT.

- Shortened project timeline by 14 months for company's largest customer by managing relationship with 3rd party vendors, saving over \$800K
- Led development of \$500K research project which was deemed a "gold standard" by the client
- Fine-tuned and developed AI/ML-based algorithms based on the results with Scikit-learn, increasing revenue 2-fold
- Performed Web Scraping over a catalog of 100K+ school supply products using mainly NodeJS and MongoDB; completed in 1 month

#### **SKILLS**

Client-Side

CSS HTML JS **Angular TypeScript** React Vue Redux **Backbone Bootstrap** 

Server-side

**Python** NumPy SciPy Eli5 Scikit-learn Keras **TensorFlow** MySQL **NodeJS Redis AWS** MongoDB Spark HTTP/2

Development & Operations

**JUnit NUnit PyUnit TestCafe** Mocha **Jest** Scrum **Agile** GIT Azure DevOps

## **PROJECTS**

#### OpenFlow based Firewall

https://github.com/danette.east/OpenFlow-Firewall OpenFlow protocol-based proactive Firewall in Python and NodeJS.

- Configured static rules using MD-SAL
- Engineered proactive rule evaluation system at OSI layer 7 using POX controller
- Provided flexibility to configure rule using centralised NodeJS based GUI

#### **STRENGTHS**

#### **Team Leadership**

Introduction to Leadership course by Harvard

#### Communication

Attended a Communication course at Stanford.